<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Ivan.fyi - personal</title>
    <subtitle>Ivan Tadeu Ferreira Antunes Filho, software engineer in Cambridge, Massachussets, Boston Area</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/tags/personal/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2020-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/tags/personal/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>10 things to smell per day</title>
        <published>2019-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/10-things-to-smell-per-day.html"/>
        <id>/10-things-to-smell-per-day.html</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="/10-things-to-smell-per-day.html">&lt;p&gt;Talking to a friend in San Francisco who is very attuned with her sense of smell made me realize that I mostly just ignore my sense of smell, to the point that I feel like I&#x27;m almost losing it. So I&#x27;ll try to keep a list of at least 10 things I&#x27;ve smelled and try to make a conscious effort into remembering it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if I generally ignore my sense of smell because I had to learn to tune it out when dealing with so many different animals and so many different types of animal poop back in the day. Seriously, it was quite horrible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;[2019-10-16_Wed]&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;timestamp-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;timestamp&quot;&gt;[2019-10-16 Wed]&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conditioner on my skin&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chips that someone opened in the airplane&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The car smell on the Uber&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sad smell that almost felt like cardboard of the chips bag I got in the plane&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The slightly better smell of the chips on the skin of my hand&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ammonia smell in the men&#x27;s bathroom&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My deodorant mixed with my own smell&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wonderful green tea smell from the green tea bag&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Green tea smell in the water&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sudden change of smell after putting sugar on the green tea.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update &lt;span class=&quot;timestamp-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;timestamp&quot;&gt;[2019-11-06 Wed] &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt; I feel like I&#x27;m a lot more in tune with my sense of smell now! It is not as great as it used to be, but it is getting better!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update &lt;span class=&quot;timestamp-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;timestamp&quot;&gt;[2020-07-09 Thu] &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt; I never really updated this, but yeah, just paying attention on smells has made me recover it; I can now tell exactly in which spot on the floor a dog has laid&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>-ARCHIVE-</title>
        <published>2019-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/archived.html"/>
        <id>/archived.html</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="/archived.html">&lt;p&gt;I have a bad memory, but I really care about lots of my friends and I want to make sure they know this. And one I try to do so is to try to keep track of what is happening in their lives so I can ask them afterwards.  I keep track of their hobbies, what big changes are happening in their lives and I write little notes in an org mode file on my laptop.
But sometimes people move away, figuratively and literally speaking;  and I know that I won&#x27;t be talking to this person anymore, maybe ever again.   Maybe the friendship was not strong enough and we were not close enough, so now that they moved out there is no reason for them to ever contact me again, and me contacting them would just be weird.  Or maybe something so horrible happened that the person should never be contacted again. Or maybe out of mutual agreement we decide that is time for things to end,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the title of this post., :ARCHIVE:. When this happens,  I archive the notes. They still exist, just as memories will always exist, but it is time to move on.  They won&#x27;t be updated anymore, and they shouldn&#x27;t be opened anymore.  In a certain way it is my own personal way of grieving, putting a period at the end of a story. Writing Fin, and putting that very last dot on the &quot;i&quot;. The way that the story ends, not with a bang, but with the silence following the last click of a keyboard key,  C&#x27;est la vie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Long name problems</title>
        <published>2019-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/long-name-problems.html"/>
        <id>/long-name-problems.html</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="/long-name-problems.html">&lt;p&gt;My name in my passport fairly long. (10 characters first name, 22 letters second name, with spaces in between). This causes me all kinds of trouble here in the US:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For 3 years in a row I had to call the IRS in order to get my tax return back; I believe it to be because the limit on the w2 forms was names of 30 characters, so my name didn&#x27;t fully match.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I used to not be able to do online check-ins into flights, but this has changed in recent years!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As I was applying for health insurance, surprise! my name was accepted. However, on the last page where you have to rewrite your name to confirm you&#x27;ve read the instructions, they did not accept spaces in the first name, only on the last name. I had to apply through email and mail after half an hour on the phone with customer service.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basically every single one of my science olympiad certificates has my name written in slightly different ways in order to make it shorter. Each remove a different part of my name.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I couldn&#x27;t signup to pay for electricity and gas through the website.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Equifax still hasn&#x27;t being able to deal with my long name, so it reports that I have no credit score. Therefore when people run a credit check on me, it is weird. Transunion has no problems with this.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When logging in the mit table tennis, I crashed the website. It tried to save my name, which was given by the mit certificate.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Blogging, past and not blogging rant</title>
        <published>2019-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2019-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/blogging-past-and-not-blogging-rant.html"/>
        <id>/blogging-past-and-not-blogging-rant.html</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="/blogging-past-and-not-blogging-rant.html">&lt;p&gt;I used to blog a lot in high school.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One blog I was really proud of was &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;olimpiadascientificas.org&#x2F;vida-de-olimpico&#x2F;ivan.olimpiadascientificas.com&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;Ivan vida de olimpico&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which was a website I wrote while I was taking part in science olympiads. The reason I wrote the website was to help incentive people to take part on science olympiads, by showing how I studied, telling stories about the competitions, showing how fun it was!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I stopped writing it, I had already reached the stage where was making my own bad drawings to better illustrate the stories&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;.&#x2F;jpg&#x2F;15647979795295734.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;.&#x2F;jpg&#x2F;15647979795295734.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;.&#x2F;jpg&#x2F;15647980113789408.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;.&#x2F;jpg&#x2F;15647980113789408.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was great! I received about 50 different visitors per day and answered comments in multiple of the posts. I had written some really great posts about motivation and study and really liked doing so.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides my main blog, I also maintained the website &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;web.archive.org&#x2F;web&#x2F;20160112231415&#x2F;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.olimpiadascientificas.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;olimpiadascientificas.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We received about 500 visits per day, from all over Brazil. It was the first Brazilian website to help students take part in science olympiads, providing study guides, hints, instructions on how to take part on them and so on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then &lt;strong&gt;what happened&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was writing study guides to help people take part in the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;olimpiadascientificas.org&#x2F;static&#x2F;pdf&#x2F;Resolu%C3%A7%C3%A3o_OBB_VII_fase2.pdf&quot;&gt;biology&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;olimpiadascientificas.org&#x2F;static&#x2F;pdf&#x2F;Linguistica0.8.pdf&quot;&gt;lynguistics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;olimpiadascientificas.org&#x2F;estudo&#x2F;fisica&#x2F;&quot;&gt;physics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, in 2012, because I had been first place in these 3 Brazilian olympiads in 2012. Taking part in these competitions and then getting to travel to other countries and make friends during the international competition was my life back in the day. They were really my life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;.&#x2F;jpg&#x2F;15647992790993993.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;.&#x2F;jpg&#x2F;15647992790993993.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, 2 Brazilian schools who used to also send students to those competitions got pissed. Why did they get pissed? Maybe they truly thought with all their good hearts that I was just a horrible person. Or maybe because they considered that I was taking spots that could be used for their students in the international competitions. Or maybe because they profited from the fact that information was not easily available, so only their students would usually do well on the competitions (together with 2 other schools), which makes making information available strictly bad to them. I don&#x27;t know, and any speculation is just speculation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So they decided to threaten the organizers of some of those competitions in order to get me kicked out from them and have their students who were in 6th place take my place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I say threaten, I do mean threaten. One of the organizers called me saying that they were threatening to sue him if he didn&#x27;t kick me out (he stopped organizing the physics olympiad in Brazil shortly afterwards because those schools were so horrible to him). To try to justify what they were doing, they used the fact that I was writing study guides to the other competitions to say that I was not dedicating myself enough on my studies, because I should be focusing on a single subject. And they used my blog and website to try to make this case, and argue that focusing on multiple subjects went against the spirit of the competition.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting fact is that those schools were also using the study guides and material that I had written…&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;.&#x2F;jpg&#x2F;15647996617704427.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;.&#x2F;jpg&#x2F;15647996617704427.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They managed to get me removed from the International Biology Olympiad team. As well as cause me so much stress that I ended up losing my best friend for not being able to keep being a social person, and abandoning them in a moment of need.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a bit rough.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the first time I had experienced that what I considered to be trying to help others could backfire, because someone profits from them not being helped. It was the first time I had someone use information I was sharing to make a dossier against me. And so the first time I saw how important privacy, even for silly things, is; and that being able to freely speak your mind is more of a privilege than a right.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for the longest time I&#x27;ve been afraid of writing stories or telling experiences. As well as extremely jaded about doing those things. I felt that writing about anything was a liability, a risk that I was no longer willing to take.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a huge part of me want this to change. A huge part of me wants to be able to just write, and tell stories and share pictures without worrying. Maybe that is just being naive and living in a fairy tale, but it brings back a bit of magic to my life. So maybe, just maybe, I will try to go back to writing these spells.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or maybe I will stay in fear of writing things online. Fear that even the smallest things could be taken out of context.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
